JAMES SULLIVAN

Software Engineer

(616) 450.9290 · jsullivan2847@gmail.com · Brooklyn, NY · LinkedIn · Github · Portfolio

I'm a software engineer with a background in audio and service. I specialize on the frontend - particularly React.js. I just finished developing a geo-location game *Hide & Seek* that uses the Google Maps API and am currently working on a project called Integrant through TOP (The Opportunity Project): a collaborative effort between the US census bureau and participating organizations to develop public facing digital products using open data. I joined the project with an entirely new engineering team. Together we've been able to pick up where the creators of the app left off and improve its performance with fresh eyes. I have a love for learning, and I value teamwork and communication. In the past I've toured as a musician and worked in fast paced kitchens. Those experiences taught me to work with a great sense of urgency and the ability to bring positive energy to any team.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS

Libraries & Frameworks - Node.js / Express, React, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Django, Unity

Database - MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL

Other - AWS Bucket, EJS, Mongoose, Git, Github, Heroku, Netlify, Postman, Google Maps API, Figma, Invision, Trello

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT / TECHNICAL PROJECTS

TOP Summer 2022 product development sprint (Integrant) | Github | App | Javascript / React / Supabase

A client based project as part of the The Opportunity Project's development program that brings developers together with open data to produce public facing digital products that are considered for federal funding through the US Census Bureau

- Built with a fully cross functional team of researchers and UX designers to meet deadlines and deliver MVP to present for funding
- Makes use of complex logic in HTML forms to deliver a user an index of grants that they qualify based on personal information.

Hide & Seek | Github | App Javascript / JQuery / HTML5 / CSS

A geographic guessing game where the user is given a random street view location and the user tries to match the location on a separate map as best they can for points, allowing users to prove how well they know their city.

- Used Google Maps API & Jquery to render dynamic maps wired with event listeners and location parameter options
- Designed the layout to be responsive via CSS media queries, grid, and flexbox.

Streepflix | Github | App | Javascript / React / MongoDB / Node / Express

A netflix clone with trailers and user profiles. Serves an index of movies from just one actress - Meryl Streep.

- React frontend with Express backend. Uses NPM packages to render a YouTube movie trailer on click.
- Worked on this project with a group as the lead front-end engineer and managed the Git repositories and deployment.

MyPix | Github | App | Python / Django / PostgreSQL / AWS Bucket

A user-based photo sharing platform

- Uses Django template views to serve a dynamic timeline of photos with user profiles
- Full CRUD app with user authentication, authorization, and AWS file upload

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Less Than 3 LLC, Production Assistant | Brooklyn, NY

January 2022 - Present

- Carpentry, painting, and design work throughout all 5 boroughs of NYC with an emphasis on floral design and seasonal decorations
 Bottle Shoppe, Wine Sales Associate | Brooklyn, NY
 March 2021 April 2022
- Maintained a well curated and extensive inventory of over 300 new and old world wines
- Provided expert recommendations for wine pairings, profiles, and personal taste to regular customers

Squibb Coffee & Wine, Cafe Manager | Grand Rapids, MI

Jan 2018 - March 2021

- Oversaw a wine, cheese, and charcuterie program, developing recipes for a scalable seasonally changing menu
- Handled customer relations, inventory management, social media and marketing
- Worked with owners of the business on big picture decisions before and throughout the pandemic

DAAC (Division Avenue Arts Collective), Sound Engineer | Grand Rapids, MI

August 2016 - March 2020

- Maintained an ever-growing database of booking contacts and scheduling in Google Sheets
- Organized and ran sound for live shows, and engineered recording sessions using multiple DAW's

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

April 2022 - July 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration.

Grand Rapids Community College | GRAND RAPIDS, MI

Associate of Science in (Architectural Technology)